gerow@mgerow.com; http://www.linkedin.com/in/gerow

http://mgerow.com; 918-740-1775

Professional Summary

A National Merit Scholar Computer Engineering and Computer Science student at USC with over four years of programming experience and over a year of experience working in a professional setting including working on IT applications/tools and embedded set top box applications. I am pursuing a career in software development.

Education

• University of Southern California—Los Angeles, CA

Majoring in Computer Engineering and Computer Science

- University GPA: 3.5, Major GPA: 3.9, Presidential Scholar
- Projected Graduation Date: May, 2014

Technical Summary

- Languages: C, Ruby, C++, Java, Go, Python, Verilog, LATEX, Motorola 68000 Assembly, Clojure, Perl
- Libraries/Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, OpenGL, ROS (Robot Operating System), OpenCV, Berkeley Sockets
- Systems/Tools: Linux and Unix variants (Debian, Ubuntu, Solaris, FreeBSD), OSX, Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7, SVN, Git, Mercurial, MongoDB, MySQL, Eclipse, Multithreaded Environments (Using Agents), Puppet, CouchDB, Apache, SLURM, Request Tracker

Professional Experience

• Information Sciences Institute—Marina del Rey, CA

Student Worker August 2013-Present

- Work on fitting virtual disk images into the current FreeBSD based disk imaging system
- **SpaceX**—Hawthorne, CA

Linux IT Intern May 2013–August 2013

- Working with Puppet backend to create a distributed report collection and node classification service in order to allow these activities to continue even if links between locations are down
- Developing a service to analyze and get statistics on tickets for the RT ticketing system
- Developing tools to help analyze high performance computing cluster usage on a SLURM cluster
- DIRECTV—El Segundo, CA

Software Engineering Intern May 2012-August 2012

- Embedded systems work with set top box UI in Java
- Creating a tool to increase productivity when working with set top box assets
- Nelson Auto Group—Tulsa, OK

Information Technology Intern May 2011-August 2011, December 2011-January 2012

- Creating a system to effectively and efficiently keep copies of all physical media needed for the company's computer and technical systems
- Creating a system to allow managers to easily access recorded calls through a web interface using PHP to access Asterisk servers

Projects Outside of School

- gnome-shell-google-calendar: Fork of script to allow Google Calendar integration into GNOME 3. Added ability to use within GNOME 3 under Ubuntu. https://github.com/gerow/gnome-shell-google-calendar
- Resume: This resume is written in LATEX. https://github.com/gerow/resume
- LittleNote: An iPhone app for sending notes to your significant other. Working on backend implemented as a Ruby on Rails application. https://github.com/kcbarry/LittleNoteWeb
- *Goose*: Database migration tool for Go. Added sqlite3 support. Currently working on support for applications that wish to target multiple database types. https://bitbucket.org/liamstask/goose
- rest-client: A REST library for ruby. Created patch to fix issue with headers being automatically renamed when they shouldn't be. https://github.com/rest-client/rest-client

Club Experience

• USC Autonomous Underwater Vehicle Team—Los Angeles, CA

Member of Software Team September 2010–May 2012

- Writing C++ code for robot running within the ROS environment under Ubuntu.
- Gained experience working with vision processing using OpenCV.